(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T21:45:50.356685",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
スバー！
Suba~!
ホロライブ2期生 大空スバル！
I'm Hololive 2nd Gen's Oozora Subaru!
今日はみんな楽しんでってね！
Everyone, have a blast today!
ちょこっとやんちゃで
A little mischievous,
にこっと元気な
smiling and cheerful,
キラッとスマイル
with a sparkling smile!
アイドル
Idol,
毎日もっと楽しくしたいとうよ
I want to make every day more fun!
Go with Adventure
ひらひらスカートも
Even fluttering skirts,
ちゃんと着こなせてるんだよ
I can pull them off properly!
だからもっともっと 好きになってもいいよ 一緒に
So feel free to fall for me more and more, together!
大空に飛び立とう
Let's take off into the vast sky!
閃光! どんな輝きの中でも
Flash! Even amidst any kind of radiance,
強いきらめき
A powerful sparkle...
君に届いているかな？
Wonder if it's reaching you?
1mmでも伝わればハイ
Even if just 1mm gets through, yes!
チャージ チャレンジ 全力アクセル!
Charge, challenge, full throttle!
頑張る君へ
To you who is trying your best,
一番のりのスマイルを送る
I'll send the very first smile,
スバルチャンネル!
Subaru Channel!
エブリデイ 悩んでい みんなで
Everyday, worrying-day, all together!
ブルーな気持ちに ズバッと駆けつけ
Dashing right to your blue feelings,
お助けしちゃうヒーロー
A hero coming to the rescue!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから
Because we can't stay faint-hearted,
強く強くで いきましょう
Let's go strong and fierce!
ハラハラ 涙拭いて
Wipe away those nervous tears,
ドキドキのときめきタイム
It's an exciting, heart-pounding time!
いつでもおいでよ 1年中パラダイス感触
Come anytime, a year-round paradise feel!
憂鬱とラフ吹き飛ばそう
Blow away the gloom and laugh it off!
閃光! どんな暗闇の中でも 眩しく照らす
Flash! Shining brightly even in any darkness!
君に見つけてもらえた
Just the fact that you found me,
それだけでも運命なんだ
That alone is destiny!
もっとずっと道は続いてく
The path keeps continuing on and on,
夢に向かって
Heading towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with me?
この手と手 走れ
Hand in hand, run!
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take everyone along!
囁く 恥ずかしいけれど
Whispering, though it's embarrassing,
伝えたい思い 今なら言える
These feelings I want to convey, I can say them now...
君のエールが力になるよ
Your cheers become my strength!
いつも元気を分けてくれて
Always sharing your energy with me,
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ
I can keep doing my best and live with a smile,
本当に
Truly!
ありがとうの気持ちを歌え
Sing out these feelings of gratitude!
どんな輝きの中でも 強いきらめき
Even amidst any radiance, a powerful sparkle!
君に届いているかな？
Wonder if it's reaching you?
1mmでも伝われ
If even 1mm gets through!
はい! もっとずっと道は続いてく
Yes! The path keeps continuing on and on,
夢に向かって
Heading towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with me?
その手と手 走れ
Hand in hand, run!
連れて行くよ みんなで
I'll take everyone along!
君と駆ける スバル
Running together with you, Subaru!
大空スバル 7周年ライブ 始まる 始まるー！
Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live is starting, starting!
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always end up causing trouble for you,
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I always end up making things so difficult,
それでも隣にいてくれる
But still, you stay by my side,
君のそばにずっと
Always right here with you.
曖昧な言葉じゃ 真面目な君には伝わらない
With vague words, I can’t get through to serious you.
頑丈なそのハートを
Your tough heart,
覗いてみたい
I want to peek inside,
溶かしてみたい
I want to melt it.
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
How about this kind of magic for times like this?
何が出るかな？
What will come out?
やっちゃえ！
Let's do it!
せーの！ try try try
Ready, set! Try try try!
あやふやだって いいの！いいの！
Even if it's uncertain, it's okay! It's okay!
Which one to pick, watch me do magic
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh my, this is turning out better than I imagined!
もう止められないのよ ごめんなさい
I can't stop now, I'm sorry!
溢れる思いで空回り
My overflowing feelings are spinning out of control,
振りかけるhappyなイメージ
Sprinkling happy images around,
で振り回すfancyなマジック
And casting fancy magic everywhere!
また君に くどくど言われちゃうけど ほら
Again, you'll probably nag me, but look,
こんなDay by dayがいい
This kind of day-by-day is perfect!
I love these kinds of day-by-days
あの日から Falling in love with you
Ever since that day, falling in love with you
変わらないから ずっと Only you
It won't change, it'll always be only you
だからほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying
掴めハッピーエンディング
Seize that happy ending
いつまでも隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep smiling by your side forever
いつも 仲間外れで
Always left out
ひとりぼっちの毎日
Every day was lonely on my own
そんな 私の前に 現れた君は
When you appeared right in front of me
同じ寂しさを 抱えている
Carrying the exact same loneliness
とても 優しい人
Such a kind-hearted person
今も心配事は多いけど
Though there are still many worries now
もう 私も君も ひとりじゃない
Neither I nor you are alone anymore
騒がしくて愛おしい この日々が
These noisy, beloved days
ずっと 続きますように
May they continue forever
3 2 1
飛ばせ happy なイメージ
Blast off that happy image!
とびきりの fancy なマジック
That ultimate fancy magic!
また君にくどくど言われそうだけれど
You'll probably nag at me again, but...
そんな Day by day がいい
I love these kinds of day-by-days
あの日から Falling in love with you
Ever since that day, falling in love with you
気付いて欲しいの Loving you
I want you to notice, loving you
だからここ うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So right here, this is no time to be dilly-dallying
次はどんなプランニング
What kind of planning next?
そしてまた 今日もハプニング
And yet another happening today!
明日はどんな おかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what funny thing will happen tomorrow
ずっと 隣で見ててね
Keep watching from right beside me forever
Happy なイメージ
Happy image
Fancy なマジック
Fancy magic
Happy なイメージ
Happy image
Fancy なマジック
Fancy magic
いっせーのーで 君とだけ！
On three, with only you!
もう少し眠りたいけど もったいないよ
I want to sleep a bit more, but it's such a waste!
今日は Sunday
Today is Sunday!
楽しいこと やりたいこと
Fun things, things I wanna do
Wake up! 始めようよ
Wake up! Let's get started!
めくりめく季節 君と
Through the dazzling seasons, with you
次のステージへ
To the next stage!
声を合わせ 扉開けて
Joining our voices, opening the door
駆け出せ 迷わずに
Dash forward without hesitation!
転んでも 格好悪くても イイじゃない
Even if we stumble or look uncool, isn't that fine?
Stand up!
イメージもっと 重ねて行く その先で
Layering our visions even more, beyond there...
いっせーのーで 君とだけ！
On three, with only you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High-five! Clap your hands
奏でるメロディーを
To the melody we play
合図に走り出せ Go!
Start running at the signal, go!
君となら怖くない
With you, I'm not afraid!
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて
High-five! Clapping hand in hand
重ねるそのメモリーは
Those memories we stack together
明日へのエネルギー
Are energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go further ahead!
君となら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a happy, lucky life!
あの日見た夢の続き
The continuation of the dream we saw that day
追いつくその日まで
Until the day we catch up to it
涙なんて 振り切るくらい
So much that we shake off all tears
もっとスピードアップ
Speed up even more!
どんな未来になっても
No matter what kind of future comes
後悔しないよ
I won't regret it!
自分自身 選んだ道
On the path I chose myself
踏み出せ 迷わずに
Step forward without hesitation!
落ち込んで 進めなくなったときは
When you're feeling down and can't move forward...
Wake up!
思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Recall the memories from back when we dreamed
手と手で奏でる
Playing hand in hand
叶える煌めく夢を 君とだけ！
Fulfilling this sparkling dream, with only you!
ハイタッチ その度に
High-five! With every single time
繋がっていく心
Our hearts connect
一人じゃないことを そう
That I'm not alone, yes...
気付かせてくれたよね
You made me realize that, didn't you?
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて
High-five! Clapping hand in hand
奏でるそのメロディーが
That melody we play together
世界に届くまで
Until it reaches the entire world
この夢は続いてく
This dream will keep going
君となら Happy Lucky Live!
With you, it's a happy, lucky live!
くじけて歩けない日は
On days you're disheartened and can't walk
おんぶしてあげる君を
I'll give you a piggyback ride
ほら見てそっちの方が
Look, that way you can
強く地面踏み込める
Step down on the ground even stronger!
巡り巡る日々を 辿り夢見たステージへ
Tracing back the passing days, towards the stage I dreamt of,
届くその日を見つめて
gaze upon the day we finally reach it,
起こそう 君とだけ!
and make it happen with only you!
手と手を鳴らす度
Every time we clap our hands,
小さなビッグバン
a little Big Bang occurs.
無限のその力を
Receiving that infinite power,
受けて進め!
push forward!
ハイタッチ
High-touch,
手たたいて
clap your hands,
奏でるメロディーを
to the playing melody.
合図に走り出せ
Run off at the signal,
Go!
君となら怖くない
I'm not scared if I'm with you!
ハイタッチ
High-touch,
手と手たたいて
clap hand in hand.
重ねるそのメモリーは
Those memories we stack up
明日へのエネルギー
become energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよもっと先へ
Come on, let's go even further!
君となら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Life!
というわけで、皆さん!
So then, everyone!
大空スバル7周年記念ライブ「ラブミ!」にお越しくださり...
Thank you so much for coming to Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live "LOVEME!"...
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
イェーイ!
Yay!
7周年ライブに来て、大空スバー! よろしくお願いします!
Welcome to my 7th anniversary live! I'm Oozora Subaru! Nice to meet you all!
ということで
And with that,
ついに「ラブミ!」が始まる、始まる!
"LOVEME!" is finally starting! It's starting!
今日のですね、配信のハッシュタグは右上のに...こちらになりますので、ぜひ
Today's stream hashtag is up on the top right... right here, so please
よろしくお願いします!
use it!
いっぱいね、大空スバル7周年ライブお付けでたくさん呟いてください!
Please tweet a lot using the Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live hashtag!
スバルもチェックしたいと思います!
Subaru will be checking them out too!
そして、皆さん!
And, everyone!
気付きましたか?
Did you notice?
なんと!
Surprise!
今までも可愛かったんですけど
I was cute before, but...
でも、より可愛くしていただきました!
They made me even cuter now!
ニュースバルです! よろしくお願いします!
It's the New Subaru! Pleased to meet you!
どうですか? 可愛い?
How is it? Am I cute?
超可愛いー!
Super cute!
ぜひですね、たくさんスクショ撮ってね
Please take lots of screenshots,
投稿してください! ポストか、ポストしてください!
and post them! Post them on X!
そしてですね、スバルにはですね
Also, for Subaru...
通常のね、スバルもね、見てほしいので、ちょっと着替えてきていいですか?
I want you to see the usual Subaru too, so can I quickly change outfit?
着替えてきます! じゃあ、行ってきます!
I'm gonna go change! Alright, see you in a bit!
うわあ! わあ!
Uwaa! Waa!
通常衣装のニュースバル!
New Subaru in my usual outfit!
そしてなんと!
And guess what!
帽子がない! ついに取れるようになった!
No cap! I can finally take it off!
やっったー! ついに取れるようになりました!
Yay! It can finally be removed!
どうですか?
How do I look?
可愛いですかー?
Is it cute~?
とてもね、より可愛く作っていただきました!
They made it look super cute for me!
髪の毛もね、サラサラー!
Look how silky my hair is!
もう本当にね、ありがとうございます!
Thank you so very much!
そして、可愛いと言えば...なんと、こちらのステージ!
Speaking of cute... check out this stage!
とてもね、可愛い! スバル、すごくゲームが好きなので
It's super cute! You know Subaru really loves video games, so...
このピクセルっぽい感じのでね、今年はね、作っていただきました!
they made this pixel-art themed stage for me this year!
イェーイ! スバルダックもいる!
Yay! Subaru Duck is here too!
そして...
And...
なんと言ってもこのピクセルのスバ友ー!
best of all, pixel-art Subatomo!
もうめっちゃ可愛いです!
They are so super cute!
色が一番見せたかったと言っても過言ではない!
It's no exaggeration to say this is what I wanted to show you most!
ということでですね、こんな素敵なステージでさせていただいて、とても幸せ...あー!
So yeah, I'm so happy to perform on such a wonderful stage... Ah!
なんと、しれっと着替えてきました!
Look, I quietly changed back!
こんにちはー!
Hello~!
やっぱね、アイドル衣装でね、やっていきたいと思います!
After all, I wanna do this in my idol outfit!
ぜひ、アイドル衣装スバルもですね
So please, take plenty of screenshots
いっぱいスクショ撮って、ポストしてください!
of Idol Outfit Subaru and post them!
よろしくお願いします!
Thank you so much!
はい、ということで、ここまではなんと
Alright, so up until now,
『プレアデス』、『Watch Me』、『ハイタッチ☆メモリー』のね、3曲をお届けしたんですけど
we've performed three songs: "Pleiades", "Watch Me", and "High-Touch☆Memory"...
全てですね、スバルにとって思い出深い楽曲です!
Every single one of them holds special memories for Subaru!
特に『プレアデス』は、絶対このニュースバルになったら
Especially "Pleiades"—once I got this New Subaru model,
一番にね、みんなにね、披露したいなと思っていたので
it was the first song I wanted to perform for everyone!
夢叶いしものでーす! めっちゃ嬉しい! ありがとうございます!
So my dream came true! I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
はい、ということで
Okay, so with that said,
もうね、ここからはですね、なんと
from here on out...
何が起こるか分からない!
anything could happen!
ゲストが
Guests might...
出てくるかもしれないし
show up, or...
出てこないかもしれない
maybe they won't!
もう何が起こるか分からない!
You really never know what will happen!
ということで
So then,
そんなね、ライブ、お楽しみに! この後も
please look forward to the live concert! Moving forward,
もうどんどんね、盛り上がって楽しんでいくぞー!
let's get super hyped up and have lots of fun!
始まる、始まるー!
Here we go, here we go~!
「わたしの全力受け止めて♡」
"Accept my full power!♡"
きゅっくん だがっちゅら めにめに
Kyukkun dagattyura meni meni
きゅっくん だがっちゅら しゅーき しゅき しゅーしゅき
Kyukkun dagattyura shuuki shuki shuushuki
きゅっきゅん らたっちゅらめにめに oh yeah
Kyukkyun ratatchura many-many oh yeah
キュンキュンキュン コクンとー？
Kyun-kyun-kyun, nodding deeply?
たとえば タイムループなんかしちゃったって
Even if we were stuck in a time loop,
運命で選んじゃうのは キ・ミ
the one I'd choose by fate is you!
(イェーイ イェーイ イェーイ)
(Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!)
わたしと 一・体・全・体・い・や・ぜっ・対！
Me and you, absolutely, completely, without a doubt!
シンデレラフィットなのは そう、キミ
The one who's a Cinderella fit is, yes, you!
(おっおーおー)
(Oh-oh-oh)
わたしが 何度も負けて落ち込んだって
Even when I lost time and again and felt down,
めげずにタックン付き合っちゃって
you stayed with me undaunted,
モチベあげるだけブチ上げちゃって
boosting my motivation all the way up!
(もうなんなん！なんなんなんなん！)
(Gosh, what is this! What, what, what, what!)
ステップアップ め〜っちゃしちゃって
Stepping up so very much,
勝手に一緒に喜び合って
rejoicing together before we knew it!
う〜…感謝してもしてもしてもたりないんじゃ〜っ！
Ugh... no amount of thanks could ever be enough~!
形だけなんてナンセンス
Just going through the motions is nonsense!
カタチないものがいいんです
Things without shape are what's truly good!
え〜っとね…それはなんといいますか
Um... how should I say this?
あ〜待って待って！今ここで伝えたいんです！
Ah, wait, wait! I want to tell you right here, right now!
拙いけど届けたい想い
Clumsy as they may be, these feelings I want to deliver...
に
to...
こんなに大きくなりました！
I've grown this big!
だから 超many-manyめな約束ド・ドッ・と・ぷり〜ず♡
So please give me a whole bunch of super many-many promises♡
もりもりmanyめに返すから！
'Cause I'll give it back to you full and plenty!
しゅーきしゅーきしゅきシュプリームなオネガイきいて！
Listen to my super-duper supreme wish!
わたし あ〜いた〜い♡
I wanna see you~♡
敬愛で超many-manyギュ〜ギュッとエールをぷり〜ず♡
Please give me super many-many tight cheers with love and respect♡
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
'Cause I'll definitely, surely return it double!
手渡しじゃ何年かかるかな
How many years would it take to hand it over in person?
ヘビーすぎじゃない？ でもいいんじゃない？？
Isn't that too heavy? But isn't it fine??
Gimme!! いつも愛をア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you as always for your love!
甘いだけじゃダメだけどね
Just being sweet isn't enough, though.
今日くらいは許してよ hum~
Forgive me at least for today, hum~
大事な話だからもうち〜〜〜〜〜っと
This is an important talk, so just a little bit more...
気合だけじゃ気絶するかな
Might I faint with just willpower alone?
誠心誠意をきいてくれますか？
Will you listen to my wholehearted sincerity?
Ah〜〜 (うぉ〜！)
Ah~~ (Woah~!)
だ・か・ら
So...
超many-manyめな約束ド・ドッ・と・ぷり〜ず♡
Please give me a whole bunch of super many-many promises♡
もりもりmanyめに返すから！
'Cause I'll give it back to you full and plenty!
しゅーきしゅーきしゅきシュプリームなオネガイきいて！
Listen to my super-duper supreme wish!
わたし あ〜いた〜い♡
I wanna see you~♡
敬愛で超many-manyギュ〜ギュッとエールをぷり〜ず♡
Please give me super many-many tight cheers with love and respect♡
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
'Cause I'll definitely, surely return it double!
手渡しで何年かかっても
Even if it takes years to hand over in person,
伝えたいじゃない！ 届けたいじゃない！
Don't you want to tell it! Don't you want to deliver it!
Gimme!! いつも愛をア・リ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you as always for your love!
キュッキュン らたっちゅらめにめに oh yeah
Kyukkyun ratatchura many-many oh yeah
キュンキュンキュン コクンとー？
Kyun-kyun-kyun, nodding deeply?
(キュンキュンキュン コクンとー？)
(Kyun-kyun-kyun, nodding deeply?)
キュンキュンキュンキュンキュンキュン！
Kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun-kyun!
ずっとよろしくね♡
Let's always be together♡
ゆらゆらり はらはらり 色とりどり 乱れ咲き
Swaying gently, fluttering down, colorful and blooming in wild profusion,
花の街 思い出す この空から
I recall the city of flowers from this sky.
ひょんな出来事から やってきたこの場所は
This place I arrived at by an unexpected turn of events
晴れ姿似合った 絢爛豪華な舞台
is a gorgeous, splendid stage fitting for my finest attire.
ハッとするほど鮮やかな世界が あるんだと知った
I learned that there's a world so vivid it takes your breath away,
あなたの無理難題に 答えていく どんな旅路に
responding to your impossible demands on whatever journey we take.
あぁ 問い合せるような答え合わせで
Ah, through a cross-checking like finding the answer,
たどり着いたその先に 新しい景色が待っているんだ
beyond where we finally arrive, a new scenery is waiting.
摩訶不思議なミステリー 次から次に起こる旅
Mysterious, profound enigmas, a journey where they occur one after another.
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみせましょう
Let us uncover even the cleverest tricks.
どんな難題でも 種明かしはあるんだ
No matter how difficult the problem, there is always a reveal.
けっして弱気にならない 必ずや導き出すから
I won't get faint-hearted, for I will surely lead the way.
あぁ この場所で触れた人の悲しみや 喜びがある
Ah, there are sorrows and joys of the people I touched in this place.
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
Each and every one of them makes my heart tremble.
ハッとするほど鮮やかな世界が ここにあるんだ
A world so vivid it takes your breath away is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 答えていく 毎日へ
Answering your impossible demands, into every day.
あぁ 問い合せるような答え合わせで
Ah, through a cross-checking like finding the answer...
たどり着いたその先に
Beyond where I've arrived,
新しい私があっているんだ
a new me is waiting.
あの頃は
Back then,
想像もしれえ
I couldn't even imagine it.
未来が咲き始めてる
The future is starting to bloom,
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
these kinds of days aren't so bad either.
ゆらゆらに ひらひらに
Swaying gently, fluttering down,
離れては寄り添って
parting and drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ
Entrusting myself to the gentle breeze,
優雅に舞う
dancing elegantly.
あの夢も アコガレも
Those dreams, those yearnings,
落書きのままボヤけて
blurring away like mere doodles,
消える寸前
right before disappearing.
「コレガイイノ？」「コレデイイノ？」
"Is this good?" "Is this enough?"
ふてくされてる鏡に
To the mirror displaying my sulking face,
何度も問いかけた
I asked myself again and again.
泣きたい日も
On days I want to cry,
くじけそうな日も
on days I feel like giving up,
乗り越えよう
let's overcome them!
希望を浴びなきゃ
Unless you bask in hope,
夢というツボミは開かないから
the bud called "dreams" will never bloom.
Are you ready GO!
走り出そう！
Let's start running!
取り急ぎ さぁ
First off, come on,
スタート！
Start!
うつむかない！
Don't look down!
ふりむかない！
Don't turn back!
明日は絶対もっとShiny!
Tomorrow will definitely be even more Shiny!
ジブン次第！
It's up to yourself!
つかめ未来！
Grasp the future!
今すぐスタートボタン
Right now, press the start button,
押してみよう
let's give it a push!
私は
I am...
こんなんじゃないはず！
I shouldn't be like this!
3 2 1 GO!
あきらめも
Giving up,
言い訳も
making excuses,
取りまとめ
bundle them all up and
リスタート！
Restart!
「たられば」に
To cling to
すがるには
"what ifs,"
まだまだ若すぎじゃない？
aren't we still way too young?
七転び
Falling seven times,
八起きでGO!
standing up eight, GO!
何度もリセットボタン
The reset button, over and over,
どんな夢も
no matter what dream,
きっと困難じゃないはず
surely it shouldn't be an obstacle!
信じてみよう
Let me believe in it!
私は
I am...
こんなんじゃないはず！
I shouldn't be like this!
3 2 1 GO!
Breakdown breakdown
Listen clear
Listen boy
Breakdown breakdown
3 2 1 Let's go!
Shining justice 芽生えて
Shining justice sprouting within,
Brand new bed town 交差する息吹
brand-new bed town where lives intersect.
岬から潮風 トンネル抜け鉄塔へ
Sea breeze from the cape, through the tunnel to the steel tower,
引かれ合い小道に迷い込む
drawn together, wandering into a narrow path.
ココロに溶け込む影 照らす黄金の“Spirits”
Shadows melting into the heart, illuminated by golden Spirits,
それは守り抜く光
that is the light to protect till the end.
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
With gathered strength, crossing even time,
1999 Bizarre Summer
巡る勇気で生きる町 Great Days
In this town living with recurring courage, Great Days!
Shining justice 芽生えて
Shining justice, sprouting anew
Breakdown, breakdown
Song of praises 響かせて
Let the song of praises ring out
Brand new town すれ違う景色
Brand-new town, passing scenery
雲の切れ間に挿す 光がほら降り注ぎ
Look, the light pouring through the broken clouds
古の小道へ 迷い込む
Wandering into an ancient alleyway
煌めき 導く街
A sparkling, guiding town
滾る黄金の Spirit
A surging golden spirit
それは果てしない 絆
An endless bond
Let the voice of love give you answer
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
With an unshakeable will, even at the moment of parting
1999 Bizarre Summer
自分乗り越え 掴み取れ 未来
Overcome yourself and seize the future
Breakdown, breakdown
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まる力で 時さえ越えて
Surpass even time with our gathered strength
Let the voice of love give you answer
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
With an unshakeable will, even at the moment of parting
1999 Bizarre Summer
交わす勇気が 生む讃歌
The courage we share creates a hymn
Breakdown, breakdown
というわけで、Great Daysをお届けしましたー！
And with that, we performed "Great Days"!
みんな楽しんでくれましたかー？
Did everyone enjoy it?
はい、ここまではですね、まず『Make it!』！
So, up until now, first was "Make it!"!
この曲は元々大好きで、絶対にやろうって決めてたんですけど
I've always loved this song and was set on performing it,
そのお陰か見事にね、ウマ娘のアプリめっちゃやるようになりました！ありがとうございます！
and thanks to that, I ended up playing the Umamusume app like crazy! Thank you!
そんな大好きな曲をですね、みんなと出来てとっても楽しかったです！ありがとうございます！
Performing such a beloved song with everyone was so much fun! Thank you!
そして続いて、『百花繚乱』でね、かっこよく踊りました！
And next, we danced coolly to "Hyakka Ryouran"!
どうでした？
How was it?
このヒラヒラがですね、結構難しく頑張ったんですけど、見てくれましたか？
These fluttering sleeves were pretty tricky, but I gave it my all—did you see it?
でもすごーくね、踊って楽しかったです！
But it was super fun to dance!
そしてですね、『こんなんじゃ...』もうこの曲はですね、夢叶しものになった時点で絶対にやろうと思ってたんですけど
And then, "Konnanjanai!"—from the moment it became a reality, I knew I had to perform this song,
ノエルちゃんとスゥーにね、もう絶対にペンライト振ってほしいと思って、要望させていただきました！
and I requested Noel-chan and Suu to wave their penlights for me!
どうだったかな、みんな楽しんでもらえたらとっても嬉しいです！
How was it? I hope everyone enjoyed it!
そして『Great Days』はですね、もうスバルの大好きなね、ジョジョ4部の曲なんですけど
And "Great Days" is a song from JoJo Part 4 that Subaru loves so much,
もう絶対ね、これでバトンを推進するんだと、こうやってぐるぐる回してね、今年飛ばさせていただいたんですけど
and I was determined to pass the baton with this, spinning it around like this and sending it flying this year too!
みんなスバルの魂と書いてプライドと読む、この魂のバトンを見ていただけましたか？もうすごかったんだから、本当に！
Did everyone catch this baton of soul—written as 'soul' and read as 'pride'? It was truly amazing!
ということで、そんなスバルのこだわりと思いがいっぱい詰まったパートにさせていただきました！
And so, this section was filled with Subaru's passion and attention to detail!
そしてなんと！ここからは、嬉しいお知らせとなっております！
And what's more! From here on, we have some wonderful announcements!
なんと、大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ販売告知ー！こちらをご覧ください！
The merch sales announcement for Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live! Please take a look at this!
グッズは4種類あります！めちゃめちゃある！ということで、早速見ていきましょう！
There are four types of merch! So many! Let me walk you through them!
イラストは、しぐれうい先生に書いていただきましたー！母ちゃん、いつもありがとー！
The illustration was drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei! Mom, thank you as always!
イラストテーマは王道アイドルスバルです！
The theme of the illustration is classic idol Subaru!
それでは、詳細を見ていきましょう！まずは、こちら！
Now, let's look at the details! First up, this!
『スバルがファンサ！ラバーマット』！
"Subaru Does Fansa! Rubber Mat"!
商の品はですね、王道アイドルスバルが描かれ...
This item features Subaru as a classic idol...
書いてあるラバーマットになります
This is the rubber mat shown right here.
以前ラバーマットを出したのはえーっと、4年前なので
The last time I released a rubber mat was... 4 years ago,
当時買えなかった人もね
so for those who couldn't buy it back then,
前の使っててもうボロボロになっちゃったよっていう人も
or those whose old one has gotten completely worn out,
ぜひ新しくチェックしてみてください！
please be sure to check this new one out!
そして続いてはこちら！
And up next is this!
スバルがファンサ！カードスリーブ！
Subaru's Fansa! Card Sleeves!
こちらはですね、ラバーマットに合わせてカードスリーブも出してみました！
For these, I decided to release card sleeves to match the rubber mat!
ラバーマットと合わせて使えばスバルに応援されているような気持ちになれるかも？
If you use them together with the rubber mat, you might feel like Subaru is cheering you on!
ということで、ぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
So please be sure to check these out too!
そして続いてはこちら！
And up next is this!
マスコット大集合カードケース！イェーイ！
Mascot Gathering Card Case! Yay!
カードスリーブときたらね、やっぱケースも必要でしょ！ということで
When you have card sleeves, you've gotta have a case too, right? So...
もうスバルのね、スバル族から
We have all of Subaru's... Subaru-zoku,
なんと綿あめウサギまで！そしてスバともも！というようなね
to Cotton Candy Rabbit, and Subatomo too!
たくさんみんなが集まったカードケースを作ってみました！
I made a card case where everyone is gathered together!
側面はですね、カードを見せつけられる窓がついているので
On the side, there's a window that lets you show off your card,
今回のカードスリーブをバシャッと挿して見せるもよし
so you can snap this card sleeve in to show it off,
その切り札を見せつけるもよし！ということで、ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください！
or flex your trump card! So please check this out as well!
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, here's this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー 動物パジャマ衣装ver.！
Plushie Keychain Animal Pajamas Outfit ver.!
こちらはですね、なんかスバル自身のぬいぐるみってあんまり出してないかも…と思って
For this, I realized, "Wait, maybe I haven't released many plushies of Subaru herself..."
ちょっとね、アイドル衣装と対になるイメージのオフっぽい動物パジャマ衣装で作ってみました！
So I made one in an off-duty style animal pajama outfit that pairs with the idol outfit!
ぜひね、このカワチイスバルもね、色んな所に連れ回してみてください！
Please take this cute Subaru around with you to various places!
そしてなんとフルセット購入特典もあります！
And what's more, there's a full set purchase bonus!
それではこちら！ドン！
Here it is! Ta-da!
ステッカーがなんとね、今回ついております！
A sticker is included this time!
とっても可愛いです！スバルずっと前からステッカー出してみたくて
It's super cute! Subaru has wanted to make a sticker for a long time,
ずっと思ってたので今回ですね、夢が叶って嬉しいです！
so I'm really happy that my dream came true this time!
ぜひみんなのお気に入りの場所にペタッと貼ってみてください！
Please stick it in your favorite spot!
そしてでは改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！ドン！
And now, once again, here is the full set! Ta-da!
やっぱりね、買うならね、シールもついてお得なフルセットのがいいかも！ということで、ぜひね、チェックしてみてください！
After all, if you're buying, the full set with the sticker bonus is a better deal! So please check it out!
以上！大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ情報でしたー！
That's all for the 7th Anniversary Live merch info!
どれもですね、素敵なグッズに仕上がっておりますので、ぜひですね要チェックだー！
All of these turned out to be wonderful merch, so please be sure to check them out!
絶対にチェックしてくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
Be sure to check them out, okay? Thank you so much!
はい！そしてですね…
Alright! And also...
なんと！この衣装での新スバル、ちょっとね可愛いのととっても、ぜひスクリーンショット撮っていただきたいです！
Wow! New Subaru in this outfit is super cute, so I'd love for you to take screenshots!
わあー！あ、そっか。後ろ向いたら撮れないや(笑)
Woah! Oh right, if I turn around you can't take one, haha.
どうぞー！
Here you go!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
スバルのこのね衣装のね、好きポイントはですね…
My favorite point about Subaru's outfit here is...
この後ろのとっても可愛い…
this super cute back...
とっても可愛いリボンがですね！
this super cute ribbon!
可愛い！
Cute!
どうですかー？
How is it?
わあー！
Woah!
可愛い！え、マジで語彙力ないな、今日(笑)
Cute! Wow, I really have no vocabulary today, haha.
でも本当に可愛いって言うんでね！
But seriously, it's just so cute!
ぜひみんながいっぱいね、ポストしてください！よろしくお願いします！
Please post a lot of screenshots, okay? Thank you!
そしてですね、こんなに楽しいライブももう、なんと終盤！わあー！
And, this fun live stream is already... heading into the home stretch! Woah!
それでここからですね、ラストに向けてですね、バーッと駆け抜けていきたいと思いますので
So from here on, as we head towards the end, I want to dash straight through at full speed!
ぜひみんなもね、最後まで楽しんでいただけてたらすごく嬉しいです！
So I'd be super happy if everyone enjoys it until the very end!
はい！ということで！
Right! So!
それじゃあもう、ラストだよ！
Alright then, it's time for the last part!
始めちゃっていいわけ？始めちゃうよ？
Is it okay to start? I'm gonna start, okay?
ということで！それじゃあですね…
So then! Well then...
はい、それでは聴いてください！
Alright then, please listen!
『ray』
"ray"
お別れしたのはもっと 前の事だったような
Saying goodbye feels like it happened so long ago
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踊りすり減らしたんだ
Locking away that sad light, I danced until my heels wore down
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
When I was with you I could see it, now it's gone from sight
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
Staring blankly at a transparent comet, yet that's all I'm searching for
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I often sang songs, melodies meant for those moments alone
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
Because I was able to feel truly lonely.
いつまで どこまでなんて
Asking "Until when?" or "How far?"...
正常か 異常か なんて
Wondering whether it's normal or abnormal...
考える暇も無い程 歩くのは大変だ
Walking is so tough there's no time to even think.
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's so much better to just have fun.
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll fake it and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't disappear even if I forget it.
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality keeps repainting the path made by ideals.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
Memories remain radiant upon that track.
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we part, and what was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を 前に長く伸ばしている
A sorrowful light stretches my shadow long in front of me.
時々熱が出るよ 時間がある時眠るよ
Sometimes I get a fever, and I sleep whenever I have time.
夢だと解るその中で 君と会ってからまた行こう
Knowing it's a dream, let's meet you in it before going on again.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear blue sky...
終わらない暗闇にも
Even in this endless darkness...
星を思い浮かべたなら すぐ銀河の中だ
If you picture stars, you're instantly in the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても 靴を新しくしても
Even if I don't cry much anymore, or get new shoes...
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't disappear even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事が きっとあったんだろうな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you.
おそらくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It's probably ordinary, but even so...
お別れした事は 出会った事と繋がっている
Our parting is connected to our meeting.
あの透明な彗星は 透明だから無くならない
That transparent comet can't disappear because it's transparent.
○×どれかなんて 皆と比べてどうかなんて
Choosing between right or wrong, or comparing with everyone else...
確かめる間も無い程 生きるんは最高だ
Being alive rocks so much there's no time to check.
あまり泣かなくなっても ごまかして笑っていくよ
Even if I don't cry much anymore, I'll fake it and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't disappear even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには 君がいる
It's okay, at the very beginning of this light, you are there.
いっせーのーせで 踏み込むゴーライン 僕らは
Ready, set, go! Stepping across the goal line, we...
何も 何も まだ知らぬ
Still know nothing, nothing at all.
一線越えて 振り返るともうない 僕らは
Crossing the line, looking back, it's already gone, we...
何も 何も まだ知らぬ
Still know nothing, nothing at all.
うだって うだって うだってく
Sweltering, pushing through, going on and on...
煌めく汗がこぼれるのさ
Glinting sweat spills over.
覚えてないことも たくさんあっただろう
There were probably many things we don't even remember.
誰も
Everyone,
彼も
even him,
シルエット
a silhouette.
大事にしてたもの
The things we held dear,
忘れたふりをしたんだよ
we pretended to forget.
なにもないよ
It's nothing,
笑えるさ
we can laugh.
いっせーのーで
Ready, set, go,
思い出す少年
the boy remembers.
僕らは
We...
何もかもを欲しがった
wanted to have it all.
わかってるって
I know,
あぁ気づいてるって
ah, I've noticed.
時計の針は
The hands of the clock,
日々は止まらない
these days don't stop.
奪って 奪って 奪っていく
Stealing away, stealing away, stealing away,
流れる時と記憶
the flowing time and memories.
遠く 遠く 遠くになって
Fading further, further, further away.
覚えてないこともたくさんあっただろう
There were probably many things we don't remember,
誰も 彼も シルエット
everyone, even him, becoming mere silhouettes.
恐れてやまぬこと 知らないふりをしたんだよ
We pretended not to know the things we feared,
なにもないよ
so we can say it's nothing,
笑えるさ
and just laugh.
ひらりとひらりと舞ってる
Fluttering, fluttering, dancing,
木の葉のように
just like the leaves of a tree,
憂うことなく焦燥もなく過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend my days without worry or impatience.
覚えてないこともたくさんあったけど
Though there were many things we don't remember,
きっとずっと変わらないものがあることを
that there are things that will surely never change,
教えてくれたあなたは
you, who taught me this,
消えぬ 消えぬ シルエット
are an unfading, unfading silhouette.
大事にしたいもの
Holding tight to what I treasure,
持って大人になるんだ
I will grow up.
どんな時も
At all times,
離さずに守り続けよう
let's protect them without ever letting go.
そしたらいつの日にか
Then someday,
なにもかもを
about everything,
笑えるさ
we'll be able to laugh.
ひらりとひらりと舞ってる
Fluttering, fluttering, dancing,
木の葉が飛んでゆく
the leaves fly away.
スターライト
[Starlight]
描いた未知の
The unknown canvas I painted,
キャンバス重ねる景色
overlapping scenery.
繋いでみて
Try connecting them,
繰り返していく衝動
this repeating impulse.
揺らいだ
Swaying,
目の前に広がる世界
the world expanding right before my eyes.
星屑のメロディ
A stardust melody,
歌に乗せた
carried upon a song.
クラッと鮮やかに
Vividly dazzling,
眩ませるように
as if blindingly bright,
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
I'll race through, Starlight!
We can fly そう 僕らは
We can fly, yes, we are...
いつしか 夢の中
Before we knew it, drawn into a dream,
惹かれて ただがむしゃらに 走り続けたよ
we just recklessly kept on running!
無限の宇宙に響いた キミを照らす声は
Echoing through the infinite universe, the voice shining on you...
どこへだって きらり 飛んでゆけるんだ
can sparkle and fly anywhere!
愉快な仲間と
With delightful friends,
歩いた非日常
walking through the extraordinary.
掴んでみて
Reach out and grab it,
指先の一等星
the first-magnitude star at your fingertips.
滲んでゆく
Blurring away,
目の前に広がった限界は
the limits expanding before my eyes.
皆の手 重ねて
Joining everyone's hands together,
ぶっ壊して
smash right through them!
吸い込まれそうな
Looking up at the night sky,
夜空を見上げて
that seems to pull me in,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
I'll shout it out now: Starlight!
I wanna be そう 僕らは
I wanna be, yes, we...
いつでも 側で 笑い合って
will always laugh together by your side.
あふれる声が 遠く こだまする
Overflowing voices echo into the distance.
願いのかけらを
The fragments of our wishes...
もしも キミの 腕を 引いて
If I pull your arm,
どこへだって きらり 飛んでゆけるんだ
Wherever we go, sparkling, we can fly there.
ちょっぴり不安な日も
Even on slightly anxious days,
魔法をかけてハッピー
I'll cast a spell and make it happy!
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with the strength of a hundred!
アクアブルーに染まる 大空めがけた
Aimed at the vast sky dyed in aqua blue,
鼓動が弾んでく
My heartbeat starts bouncing!
We can fly
そう僕らは この日をずっと 待ってたんだ
Yes, we've been waiting for this day all along.
まだ 醒めないで Starlight
Don't wake up yet, Starlight!
僕らは 止まらない その光が消える
We won't stop, until that light fades,
1秒前まで 走り続けるよ
Until one second before, I'll keep running!
無限の 宇宙に 響いた
Echoing in the infinite universe,
キミを 照らす 声を 強く抱いて
Hold tightly to the voice that shines on you,
きらり 輝いてゆけ
Sparkle and shine on!
いつだって愛情が先に 走り出す 僕らのランウェイを
Love always takes off running first along our runway.
頑丈とラッキーを盾に 進みます ア ユ レディ?
Advancing with toughness and luck as shields! Are you ready?
転んだって泣いたって僕ら 慣れてるよ 受け身はパーフェクト
Even if we fall or cry, we're used to it, our breakfalls are perfect!
笑ってくれてありがとう！ また僕は歌えるよ
Thank you for smiling! Now I can sing again!
人生は 不安ばっか 正直 自信は ないけど
Life is full of anxiety, and honestly I lack confidence, but...
君の 隣だけは 譲る気は ないのです！
The spot right beside you is the one thing I won't give up!
僕らが 出会えた 奇跡の セカイ 君の目に どう映るかな
How does this miraculous world where we met look in your eyes?
青より 澄み渡る 僕だけの 大空だといいな
I hope it's a sky clearest of all blues, one just for me.
不確かな 永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす 今を歌いたいんだ
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to sing about this moment spent together.
この 惑星の 片隅続く あいまい ミーゆえに ラブ ミー
Continuing in a corner of this planet, an ambiguous me, so love me!
ナンセンスな現実が 心を乱していった
Nonsensical reality was disturbing my heart.
ラッキーの天秤の裏側にある アンラッキー
The unluckiness that sits on the flip side of luck's scales.
転んだって泣いたって僕ら 立ち上がる 七転八倒さ
Even if we fall or cry, we stand right back up—struggling through seven falls and eight rises!
笑ってくれてありがとう！ まだ僕は走れるよ
Thank you for smiling! I can still keep running!
人生の 期待感は 正直 膨らむ ばっかでさ
To be honest, my expectations for life just keep growing...
君の 心の中 灯る ひだまりなの で
Because it's a warm spot lighting up inside your heart,
僕らが 暮らしてる 奇跡の 時代 君のこと どう照らすかな
How will this miraculous era we live in shine upon you?
昼より 煌めいた 僕らしい 太陽に なれたら
If only I could become a sun like myself, sparkling brighter than midday.
不確かな 永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす 今を楽しんでいたい
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to enjoy this moment spent together!
この 惑星の 片隅続く あいまい ミーゆえに 斬新
Continuing in a corner of this planet, an ambiguous me, so novel!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for today!
ここまで活動できたのは 応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
Being able to carry on my activities until now is all thanks to everyone who supported me!
いつも本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much as always!
みんなー、大好きだぞー！
Everyone, I love you all so much!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey!
ああ健やかな時も ああ病める時もきっと 伝えたいよこのメロディー
Ah, whether in health or in sickness, I surely want to convey this melody to you!
僕らが 出会えた 奇跡の セカイ 君の目に どう映るかな
How does this miraculous world where we met look in your eyes?
青より 澄み渡る 僕だけの 大空だといいな
I hope it's a sky clearest of all blues, one just for me.
不確かな 永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす 今を歌いたいんだ
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to sing about this moment spent together.
この 惑星の 片隅続く あいまい ミーゆえに ラブ ミー アイ ラブ ユー 伝え たいの！
Continuing in a corner of this planet, an ambiguous me, so love me! I want to tell you I love you!
いつだって愛情が走り出す
Love always takes the lead and starts running
僕らのランウェイを
on our runway.
頑丈とラッキーを盾に進みます
We press on using resilience and luck as our shield.
アー ユー レディー？
Are you ready?
転んだって泣いたって僕ら慣れてるよ
Even if we fall or cry, we're used to it—
受身はパーフェクト
our breakfalls are perfect!
笑ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for smiling with me!
また僕は歌えるよ
I can sing once again.
人生は不安ばっか
Life is full of anxieties,
正直自信はないけど
and honestly, I lack confidence,
君の隣だけは譲る気はないのです！
but I won't give up the spot right beside you!
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
In this miraculous world where we met,
君の目にどう映るかな
I wonder how it looks in your eyes.
青より澄み渡る僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's a clear sky just for me, even bluer than blue.
不確かな永遠より
Rather than an uncertain eternity,
僕は二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
I want to sing about the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅
In a corner of this planet,
続くあいまいミーゆえにラブミー
an ambiguous "me" continues, so love me!
ナンセンスな現実が心を乱していった
Nonsensical reality started troubling my heart.
ラッキーの天秤の裏側にあるアンラッキー
Bad luck lies on the flip side of luck's scales.
転んだって泣いたって僕ら立ち上がる
Even if we fall or cry, we'll stand right back up.
七転八倒さ
We fall seven times and get up eight!
笑ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for smiling with me!
まだ僕は走れるよ
I can still keep running.
人生の期待感は
My expectations for life
正直膨らむばっかでさ
honestly just keep growing,
君の心の中灯るひだまりなのです
becoming a warm sunny spot lit in your heart.
僕らが暮らしてる奇跡の時代
In this miraculous era we live in,
君のコトどう照らすかな
I wonder how it will shine upon you.
星より煌めいた僕らしい太陽になれたら
If I could become a sun true to myself, shining brighter than the stars...
不確かな永遠より
Rather than an uncertain eternity,
僕は二人で過ごす今を楽しんでいたい
I want to enjoy the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅
In a corner of this planet,
続くあいまいミーゆえにダンシング
an ambiguous "me" continues, so keep dancing!
ああ健やかな時も
Ah, whether in times of health,
ああ病める時も
ah, or in times of sickness,
きっと伝えたいよこのメロディー
I definitely want to convey this melody to you.
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
In this miraculous world where we met,
君の目にどう映るかな
I wonder how it looks in your eyes.
青より澄み渡る僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's a clear sky just for me, even bluer than blue.
これからも、楽しい事いっぱい一緒にしようね！
Let's keep doing lots of fun things together!